Let's begin by investigating how deep learning can
我们先来研究下深度学习可以如何用来
be used to recognize handwritten numerical digits.
识别手写的数字
We'll design in image classification algorithm that takes pictures of
我们将设计一个图片分类算法
handwritten numbers and identifies the numbers represented in the images.
该算法会对手写数字进行拍照 并识别图片中的数字
To do this, we'll use the MNIST Database which
为此 我们将使用 MNIST 数据集
contains 70000 grayscale images of handwritten digits.
其中包含了 70000 个手写数字灰度图片
Each depicts one of the numbers zero through nine.
每幅图片都描述了一个从 0 到 9 的数字
This database is perhaps one of
该数据集或许是
the most famous databases in the field of machine learning.
机器学习领域最有名的数据集之一
We'll work with this data set for the next few videos.
在接下来的几个视频中 我们都将用到该数据集
You're strongly encouraged to follow along in the Jupyter notebook linked below.
强烈建议你按照下面链接的 Jupyter notebook 跟着操作
It's relatively straightforward to download MNIST in Keras.
在 Keras 中下载 MNIST 比较简单
After importing the necessary python module,
导入必要的 python 模块后
it's only one line of code to get
只需一行代码就能开始获得
our train and test images along with their corresponding labels.
我们的训练和测试图片以及相应的标签
When we look at the first six training images,
查看了前六幅训练图片之后
we immediately notice that some digits are more legible than others.
很快就会发现某些数字更容易看清
If you squint just right the nine could pass for a four,
稍微眯下眼 9 就可能看成了 4
and you can imagine that the data set may
可以想象数据集中的某些 3
contain some threes that could pass for eight's.
看起来会像 8
Our algorithm will have to conquer these difficulties.
我们的算法需要克服这些难题
To accomplish our task we need to train an algorithm that
为了完成我们的任务 我们需要训练一个算法
can examine the images and discover patterns.
该算法能够检查图片并发现规律
It will need to attain some level of
它需要从某种程度上了解
understanding for what makes a hand-drawn one look like a one,
手写的 1 怎样才看起来像 1
and how images of ones differ from images of twos or threes.
数字 1 和数字 2 或 3 有何区别
These discovered patterns can then be used to
这些规律可以用来
decipher the digits in images that it hasn't seen before.
解读尚未见过的图片中的数字
To begin, let's check what a computer sees when we input one of these images.
首先我们看看 当我们输入其中一个图片 计算机看到的是什么
Any grayscale image is interpreted by the computer
计算机会将任何灰度图片解读为一个矩阵
as a matrix with one entry for each image pixel.
每个图片像素对应一项
Each image in the MNIST Database is 28 pixels high and 28 pixels wide,
MNIST 数据集中的每个图片宽和高均为 28 像素
and so understood by the computer as a 28 by 28 matrix.
因此计算机将其看做 28 x 28 的矩阵
White pixels are encoded as 255.
白色像素编码为 255
Black pixels are encoded as 0.
黑色像素编码为 0
And gray pixels appear in the matrix as an integer somewhere in between.
灰色像素在矩阵中显示为二者之间的整数
As a quick preprocessing step,
我们将对图片进行快速预处理
we'll rescale each image to instead have values in the range from 0 to 1.
调整每个图片 使值位于 0 到 1 之间
To do this, we'll divide every pixel in every image by 255.
为此 我们将每个图片中的每个像素除以 255
Before supplying the data to a deep network in Keras,
在将数据应用到 Keras 中的深度网络之前
we'll also need to preprocess the labels.
我们还需要预处理标签
Currently, each image has a label that's integer valued.
目前 每个图片拥有一个整数标签
We'll need to convert this to a one-hot encoding.
我们需要将其转换为一位one-hot 编码
Each label will be transformed to a vector with mostly zeros.
每个标签将被转换为一个大部分值为 0 的向量
If the label was originally a 7,
如果原始标签是 7
we'll put a 1 in the seventh entry of the vector.
我们将在向量的第七项里放入 1
Our second training image depicts a 3,
我们的第二个训练图片描述的是 3
so I'll put a 1 in the third entry of its label vector, and so on.
所以在标签向量的第三项里放入 1 以此类推
We do this in cell 5 of the Jupyter notebook.
我们在 Jupyter 计算机本的第 5 个 cell 里执行此操作
Now that our data appears to be sufficiently preprocessed,
注意 我们的数据似乎已经完全预处理了
do you think we can use the neural networks from the previous lesson?
你认为我们可以使用上节课的神经网络吗？
Could we just input this image data to an MLP and operate as we
我们可以将此图片输入到 MLP 中
did before when we were doing classification? Not exactly.
然后像之前的分类操作那样进行操作吗？不可以
Recall that MLPs only take vectors as input.
注意 MLP 仅需要向量输入
So in order to use an MLP with images,
因此要向 MLP 输入图片
which you've seen are encoded as matrices,
可以看到已经编码为矩阵
we have to first convert all of our matrices to vectors.
我们首先需要将矩阵转换为向量
We'll illustrate this conversion process on the toy example depicted here.
我们将用这里描述的小例子来演示这一转换流程
In the case of a 4 by 4 image we can construct a vector with 16 entries.
对于 4 x 4 的图片 我们可以构建一个具有 16 个项目的向量
Where the first four entries of our vector correspond to the first row of our old matrix.
前四个项目对应的是矩阵的第一行
The second four entries correspond to the second row and so on.
下一批四个项目对应的是第二行 以此类推
In the case of our 28 by 28 matrices,
对于 28 x 28 的矩阵
will flatten them to a vector with 784 entries.
将扁平化为具有 784 个项目的向量
After encoding our images as vectors,
将图片编码为向量后
they can be fed into the input layer of an MLP.
就可以传入 MLP 的输入层了
We'll do this in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中完成这一步